A Guide to the William Stanley Braithwaite Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8990-b
William Stanley Braithwaite Papers 1882-1970
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8990-b
7 ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1985 Jul 3
Biography
BIOGRAPHICAL CHRONOLOGY OF WILLIAM STANLEY BRAITHWAITE
1875 Marriage of William Stanley Braithwaite's parents Emma DeWolfe (1860-1928) and William Smith Braithwaite (1853-1886)
1876 Birth of William Stanley Braithwaite's sister, Eva Braithwaite
1878 Birth of William Stanley Braithwaite in Boston, Massachusetts on 6 December
1885 Birth of a sister; she dies in 1894
1886 Death of William Stanley Braithwaite's father
1889 Map of Europe drawn by William Stanley Braithwaite is exhibited at the Paris fair
1890 William Stanley Braithwaite, age 12, obtains first job (selling newspapers in Boston)
1898 William Stanley Braithwaite manages a Newport, Rhode Island bookstore
1901 Publishes first novel,
The Canadian, A Novel
1903 Marries Emma Kelly on 30 June; seven children: Fiona Lydia Rossetti Braithwaite(Mrs. Merrill Carter), Katherine Keats Braithwaite(Mrs. William J. Arnold), William Stanley Braithwaite, Jr., Edith Carman Braithwaite(Mrs. Agard), Paul Ledoux Braithwaite, Arnold DeWolfe Braithwaite, Francis Robinson Braithwaite
1904 Publishes
Lyrics of Life and Love
1906 Edits
The Book of Elizabethan Verse
elected to the Boston Author's Club with the support of Thomas Wentworth Higginson and Julia Ward Howe; begins writing for the
Boston Evening Transcript
on 14 February; he reviews American poetry and poets and writes essays
1907 William Stanley Braithwaite poem "White Magic", honoring John Greenleaf Whittier, is read by Braithwaite at Faneuil Hall, Boston, Massachusetts on 17 December
1908 Publishes
The House of Falling Leaves
writes an essay introduction for
The Wounded Eros: Sonnets
by Charles Gibson
1909 Publishes poem "Sandy Star" in the July issue of
Atlantic Monthly
also edits
The Book of Georgian Verse
1909-1910 Plans
"The Book of Victorian Verse"
but it is never published
1910 Edits
The Book of Restoration Verse
1912-1914 Sporadically publishes and edits
Poetry Journal
until it is taken over by others
1913-1929 Edits
Anthology of Magazine Verse and Yearbook of American Poetry For The Year...
until 1929
1915 William Stanley Braithwaite poem "The Mystery" is published in the October issue of
Scribners
literary criticism by Braithwaite is published in
The Poetry Journal
,
"Poetry of The Public"
he organizes the New England Poetry Club with Edward J. O'Brien
1916 Edits
Representative American Poetry
with Henry Thomas Schittkind; also edits
The Poetic Year For 1916
and
The Poets of The Future: A College Anthology of 1915/16
1916-1917 Edits
The Stratford Monthly
with Henry Thomas Schnittkind
1917 Plans a book,
"The Seven Wisdoms of Grainne"
but does not complete it; accepts honorary membership in Alpha Phi Alpha fraternity
1918 Awarded the Spingarn Medal, First Baptist Church, Providence, Rhode Island, during a meeting of the National Association For The Advancement of Colored People(NAACP) on 3 May for "distinguished achievement in literature"; edits
The Golden Treasury of Magazine Verse
awarded an honorary A. M. (Masters) degree from Atlanta University for his poetry and a Litt.D. from Talladega College; writes introduction to
The Heart of A Woman And Other Poems
by Georgia D. Johnson
1919 Publishes
The Story of The Great War
edits
Victory! Celebrated By Thirty-eight American Poets
literary criticism published in
The Crisis
, "Some Contemporary Poets of The Negro Race"; edits
The Book of Modern British Verse
1920 Publishes
Our Essayists And Critics Today
1921 Writes introduction to
The Beggars' Vision
by Brookes More; publishes poetry volume,
A Tale Of A Walled Town And Other Verses
1921-1927 Founds and becomes editor-in-chief of B. J. Brimmer Publishing Company with Winifred Jackson as a partner and company treasurer; she buys the company in 1925, the same year of its bankruptcy(?) (Several documents in the collection indicate the company may have remained solvent until 1929.)
1922 William Stanley Braithwaite edits
Anthology of Massachusetts Poets
B. J. Brimmer publishes
Bronze: A Book of Verse
by Georgia Douglas Johnson
1924 B. J. Brimmer publishes
Confusion
by James Gould Cozzens; William Stanley Braithwaite publishes "The New Negro In Literature" in
The Crisis
, and,
Going Over Tindal, A Novel
1928 Death of William Stanley Braithwaite's mother; he publishes a book of stories,
Frost On The Green Leaf
1931 Edits
Our Lady's Choir: A Contemporary Anthology of Verses By Catholic Sisters
1934 Literary criticism, "The Novels of Jessie Faust," published in
Opportunity
1934-1935 Appointed Professor of Creative Literature at Atlanta University; retires in 1945
1935 Alan F. Peter of the Poetry Digest Association plans a 1935 issue of
Anthology of Magazine Verse
and offers William Stanley Braithwaite the opportunity of providing editorial assistance
1936 William Stanley Braithwaite writes introduction to
We Lift Our Voices And Other Poems
by Mae V. Cowdery
1937 Sterling Brown, in
Negro Poetry & Drama
, praises William Stanley Braithwaite as a poetry critic
1938 William Stanley Braithwaite serves on a program committee for the Association of Teachers of English in Negro Colleges(later The College Language Association)
1939 Death of William Stanley Braithwaite's paternal uncle, Edward John Braithwaite, age 85, in September
1940 William Stanley Braithwaite publishes
The Years Between 1918-39
and
Poems, New and Selected
1941-1942 William Stanley Braithwaite's autobiography,
"The House Under Acturus"
is serialized in five installments in
Phylon
during 1942; it tells the story of his life up to the publication of his first book of poems in 1904
1942 An M. A. thesis by Alma Westine Stone of Atlanta University examines William Stanley Braithwaite's career
1945 Retires from Atlanta University and moves to Harlem, New York City
1947 Publishes an article in
Negro Digest
, "Negro America's First Magazine"
1948 Publishes
Selected Poems
1950 Publishes
The Bewitched Parsonage: The Story of The Brontes
1956 Interviewed by Columbia University's Oral History Research Office from May to June:
"The Reminiscences of William S. Braithwaite"
1957 Literary criticism published in
Phylon
, "Alain Locke's Relationship To The Negro In American Literature"; death of William Stanley Braithwaite's brother Arthur on 24 September
1958 Co-edits 1958
Anthology of Magazine Verse
with Margaret Carpenter, a Norfolk, Virginia, poet and admirer; it includes a selection of poetry from the previous anthologies; William Stanley Braithwaite's efforts are hampered by his failing eyesight
1959 An American Poetry Society dinner is held in William Stanley Braithwaite's honor in New York City; he writes the preface to
A Voice In Ramah: Poems
by Marion Buchman
1962 Death of William Stanley Braithwaite, age 83, on 8 June in New York City; funeral held on 12 June
Container List
- SERIES I: MANUSCRIPTS OF WILLIAM STANLEY BRAITHWAITE
  - "Another Year of American Poetry In Review" (Boston Evening Transcript ), 1912, 1918, 1924 (Box Box 1)
  - Anthology of Massachusetts Poets: Letters and related items, 1922 & 1930 (Box Box 1)
  - The Bewitched Parsonage: The Story of The Brontes -- title pages, contents, and photograph, ca. 1950 (Box Box 1)
  - The Book of Elizabethan Verse: Letters and related items, 1906-1907, 1910 & 1935 (Box Box 1)
  - The Book of Georgian Verse: Letters, 1908-1909 (Box Box 1)
  - The Book of Modern British Verse: Miscellaneous Manuscripts, ca. 1919 (Box Box 1)
  - "The Book of Victorian Verse": Permissions to quote, 1909-1910 (Box Box 1)
  - "The Book of Victorian Verse": typed manuscript, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Book Reviews by William Stanley Braithwaite, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 1)
  - Criticism, Essays and Reviews, 1912, 1916, 1929, 1934, 1947 (Box Box 1)
  - The Golden Treasury of Magazine Verse: Applications for permission to publish, 1918 (Box Box 1)
  - The Golden Treasury of Magazine Verse: Galley Proof, 1918 (Box Box 1)
  - The House of Falling Leaves: Letters to William Stanley Braithwaite, 1907-1908 & 1909 (Box Box 1)
  - Journal of American Poetry: The Poetry Weekly --Galley Proofs, 1928 July (Box Box 1)
  - "Letters In New England"-- William Stanley Braithwaite lecture? (Box Box 1)
  - Lyrics of Life and Love: Letters to William Stanley Braithwaite, 1897, 1904-1905 & 1911 (Box Box 1)
  - "Manuscript Record for 1911" (Box Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1887-1933, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts of William Stanley Braithwaite, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Our Lady's Choir: A Contemporary Anthology of Verse By Catholic Sisters: carbons of poems w/related items, 1932 (Box Box 2)
  - "The Poems Of The Month", 1921 & n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - The Poetic year 1916: A Critical Anthology --permissions to publish poems, 1917 (Box Box 2)
  - Poems of William Stanley Braithwaite?, 1907, 1932-1959 (Box Box 2)
  - Proposed Books by William Stanley Braithwaite, 1910, 1921-1933 (Box Box 2)
  - Sandy Star: A Book Of Poems --Advertisements and Lithographs for limited autograph editions, ca. 1928 (Box Box 2)
  - The Reminiscences of William S. Braithwaite, Columbia University, Oral History Research Office, pp. 1-209, 1956 May-June; TMs, 2 folders (Box Box 2)
  - The Reminiscences of William S. Braithwaite, Columbia University, Oral History Research Office, pp. 1-233, 1956 May-June; TMs(carbons), 2 folders (Box Box 2)
  - Scrapbook of William Stanley Braithwaite, w/clippings of his essays and reviews, 1907-1917 (Box Box 3)
  - Materials removed from William Stanley Braithwaite's scrapbook re his essays and reviews, 1907-1917 (Box Box 3)
  - The Story of The Great War: Royalty Reports, 1919, 1923-1935 (Box Box 3)
  - Walt Whitman Tribute by William Stanley Braithwaite: Letters w/related items, 1919 (Box Box 3)
- SERIES II: ANTHOLOGY OF MAGAZINE VERSE
  - Anthologies: Letters and related papers, 1904-1912 (Box Box 3)
  - Anthology/Book Materials, 1925-1928 (Box Box 3)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse: Poems reviewed by William Stanley Braithwaite for possible inclusion, 1911-1938, n.d.; 3 folders (Box Box 3)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse: Poems reviewed by William Stanley Braithwaite for possible inclusion, n.d. (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse: Correspondence and related items, 1912-1936 (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse: Correspondence, 1914-1929, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse: Unbound Pages, 1913 (Box Box 4)
  - Scrapbook of William Stanley Braithwaite, w/reviews of his Anthology of Magazine Verse, 1913-1919 (Box Box 4)
  - Loose materials from William Stanley Braithwaite's scrapbook of reviews re Anthology of Magazine Verse, 1913-1919 (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1914: Galley Proofs (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1915: Announcements, 1915 Aug 17 (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1915: Manuscripts (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1917: First author galley proofs (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1917: Original Manuscript (Box Box 4)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1917: Unbound Pages (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1918: Galley Proofs and unbound pages (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1918: Unbound Pages (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1919: Letters (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1921: Letters (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1922: Correspondence (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1923: Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1924: Correspondence (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1925: Correspondence and related items (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1926: Correspondence and related papers, 1926 Jan--Dec 22 & 1928, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1927: Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1928: Correspondence, 1928 & 1930 (Box Box 5)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1929: Correspondence, 1929-1931; 2 folders (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1929: Miscellaneous Letters, 1929-1930 (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1929: Permissions to quote, 1929 June-Sep; 2 folders (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1929: Special Pre-Publication Subscription Offer (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1935 (not issued by William Stanley Braithwaite) (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1958: Page (and galley?) proofs (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1958: Subscription Offer (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1958: Poet Autographs (Box Box 6)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse 1958: Permission Letters to poets, 1958-1959 (Box Box 6)
- SERIES III: B. J. BRIMMER COMPANY
  - B. J. Brimmer Co.: Correspondence and related papers, 1914-1927 Oct; 5 folders (Box Box 7)
  - B. J. Brimmer Co.: Correspondence and related papers, 1927 Nov--1936, n.d.; 3 folders (Box Box 8)
  - B. J. Brimmer Ledger, 1925-1926 (Box Box 8)
  - Emma E. Colley's and Winifred Davidson's Unfamiliar Quotations --correspondence, 1916, 1925-1926, n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Elizabeth Weston Timlow's The Heart of Monadnock --correspondence, 1922-1923 & 1926 (Box Box 8)
  - Lewis Carroll's Novelty And Romancement: Announcement and manuscript, 1925 (Box Box 8)
  - Evelyn H. Watson's "Flame Wings"--correspondence, 1925 & n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Bella Flaccus' If I Were Pan: Correspondence w/ William Stanley Braithwaite and page proofs, 1927-1928 (Box Box 8)
  - George H. P. Gannaway's "Continuance": Letter to William Stanley Braithwaite and corrected manuscript, 1928 & 1935 (Box Box 8)
  - Book Advertisements--drafts by William Stanley Braithwaite, n.d. (Box Box 8)
- SERIES IV: CORRESPONDENCE OF WILLIAM STANLEY BRAITHWAITE
  - Subseries A: William Stanley Braithwaite and his miscellaneous correspondence
    - Correspondence of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1899-1921; 6 folders (Box Box 9)
      [Includes form letter from Edmund Clarence Stedman; a letter from William Stanley Braithwaite to a Mr. McCourtie, 9 January 1919, pertaining to a speaking engagement for the Poetry Society and mentions Lady Leonora Speyer. ]
    - Correspondence of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1922-1929; 5 folders (Box Box 10)
    - Correspondence of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1930-1939; 4 folders (Box Box 11)
    - Correspondence of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1951, 1952, 1955, 1958, n.d.; 3 folders (Box Box 11)
      [including 80th birthday congratulations from Mark Van Doren]
    - Early Acceptances and Rejections, 1897-1938, n.d. (Box Box 12)
    - Physicians' Letters to William Stanley Braithwaite, 1900, 1913, 1921 & 1927 (Box Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1904-1934 (Box Box 12)
      [including copy of a Nicholas Vachel Lindsay letter 1917 January 1 re
      Birth of A Nation
      and Southern racism]
    - Letters to William Stanley Braithwaite requesting permission to publish his poems, 1905, 1921-1926, 1938 (Box Box 12)
    - Correspondence: "Persons of special interest", 1921-1936 (Box Box 12)
    - Correspondent's List, 1922-1935 & 1962 (Box Box 12)
    - Letters to William Stanley Braithwaite--fragments and missing pages (Box Box 12)
  - Subseries B: Braithwaite Family and related papers
    - Arnold Braithwaite[brother], 1906, 1934-1935 (Box Box 12)
    - Arnold DeWolfe Braithwaite[son], 1933, 1936-1937, 1939 (Box Box 12)
    - Edith Carman Braithwaite[daughter], 1929-1937 (Box Box 12)
    - Edward John Braithwaite[uncle], 1891-1930 (Box Box 12)
    - Emma DeWolfe Braithwaite[mother], 1891-1935 (Box Box 12)
    - Emma Kelly Braithwaite[wife], 1901-1913 (Box Box 12)
    - Emma Kelly Braithwaite[wife], 1918-1939, n.d. (Box Box 13)
      [Including a 1934 November 2 letter from W. E. B. Du Bois--attached to letter, 8 November 1934]
    - Letters of William Stanley Braithwaite to his wife Emma, 1902-1936 Feb; 3 folders (Box Box 13)
    - Letters of William Stanley Braithwaite to his wife Emma, 1936 Mar-1938, n.d. (Box Box 14)
    - Fiona Lydia Braithwaite[daughter], 1912-1936, n.d.; 4 folders (Box Box 14)
    - Francis Robinson Braithwaite[son], 1937 (Box Box 14)
    - Katherine Keats Braithwaite[daughter], 1920-1936 (Box Box 14)
    - Paul Ledoux Braithwaite[son], 1935-1937 (Box Box 14)
    - William Stanley Braithwaite, Jr.[son], 1925-1935 (Box Box 14)
    - William Stanley Braithwaite, Jr., 1936-1937 (Box Box 15)
    - Lillian K. Coleman, Lillian Valentine[sister-in-law?], 1926-1939 (Box Box 15)
    - Sadie De Wolfe (Braithwaite)[aunt], 1904-1911, 1928 & 1938 (Box Box 15)
    - Sally Kelly[mother or grandmother of wife], 1900, 1903, 1909-1912 (Box Box 15)
    - Lucy Williams[aunt of William Stanley Braithwaite's wife], 1935-1936 (Box Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous Braithwaite Family Letters, 1893 & 1907 (Box Box 15)
    - School Papers--Braithwaite children, 1913, 1921-1929 (Box Box 15)
    - Braithwaite Family Photographs, 1913 & 1929, 1942, n.d. (Box Box 15)
    - Photographs of William Stanley Braithwaite, [1882], 1942 (Box Box 15)
    - Lithographs of William Stanley Braithwaite, ca. 1928 (Box Box 15)
  - Subseries C: Name Files
    - Richard G. Badger, 1904 & 1915-1916 (Box Box 15)
    - Maurine Boie, 1929-1933 (Box Box 15)
    - Witter Bynner, 1922 & 1924 (Box Box 15)
    - Bliss Carman, 1911 (Box Box 15)
    - William Stanley Braithwaite Letters to Margaret Carpenter, 1956-1958 July; 2 folders (Box Box 15)
    - William Stanley Braithwaite Letters to Margaret Carpenter, 1958 Aug-1959; 2 folders (Box Box 16)
    - Charlotte, 1920-1922 & 1935, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 16)
    - Joy Gerbaulet Clairmonte, 1929-1931 & 1947-1970; 2 folders (Box Box 16)
    - Ruby Rose Drake: Correspondence and related book material, 1927, 1934-1937, n.d. (Box Box 16)
    - Sophie Hagemann Duckworth, 1922 (Box Box 16)
    - George Elliston, 1928-1929 (Box Box 16)
    - Eva Knox Evans, 1934-1935 & 1939 (Box Box 17)
    - Ernst B. Filsinger, 1916 & 1922 (Box Box 17)
    - Elizabeth Hollister Frost, 1928-1930 (Box Box 17)
    - Marion P. Gale, 1930 & 1935-1938 (Box Box 17)
    - E. V. H., 1934-1935 (Box Box 17)
    - Iva L. Handy, 1935 (Box Box 17)
    - Henry E. Harman, 1913-1914, n.d. (Box Box 17)
    - Helen, 1920-1921 (Box Box 17)
    - John Hughes, 1922-1937 (Box Box 17)
    - Mitchell Kennerly, 1911-1915 & 1922 (Box Box 17)
    - Helen Kent, 1930-1938, n.d.; 3 folders (Box Box 17)
    - Helen Kent: Writings and Miscellaneous Papers, 1929-1931, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 18)
    - Frederic Lawrence Knowles, 1904-1908, 1921 & 1928 (Box Box 18)
    - Mary Sinton Leitch, 1926, 1929, 1937 (Box Box 18)
    - L. W., n.d. (Box Box 18)
    - Margaret, 1936 (Box Box 18)
    - Francis Mason, 1923 & 1925 (Box Box 18)
    - Edith Mirick, 1920, 1929, 1930-1931, n.d. (Box Box 18)
    - Peg ( Winifred V. Jackson?), 1930-1938 (Box Box 18)
    - Edwin Arlington Robinson, 1929 & 1935 (Box Box 18)
    - Edna Davis Romig, 1926-1930 (Box Box 18)
    - Rose/Rosa, 1921 (Box Box 18)
    - Lew Sarett, 1919, 1921-1927 (Box Box 18)
    - Henry Thomas Schnittkind( The Stratford Journal ), 1916-1917 (Box Box 18)
    - Edmund Clarence Stedman, 1900 (Box Box 18)
    - Sara Teasdale, 1912-1913 (Box Box 18)
    - Eunice Tietjens, 1929 (Box Box 18)
    - Mary Pollard Tynes, 1929-1931 (Box Box 18)
    - Louis Untermeyer, 1922 & 1926 (Box Box 19)
    - Arthur Upson, 1906-1909 (Box Box 19)
    - Henry Van Dyke, 1912, 1917, 1934 (Box Box 19)
    - Harold Vinal, 1922 & 1926-1928 (Box Box 19)
  - Subseries D: Topical Files
    - Atlanta University, 1932-1944, n.d.; 3 folders (Box Box 19)
    - Author's League of America, 1916-1918 & 1924 (Box Box 19)
    - Boston Evening Transcript, 1907-1930 (Box Box 19)
    - Boston Author's Club& New England Poetry Club, 1906-1934, n.d. (Box Box 19)
    - Brentano's(Publisher), 1907-1925, 1935 (Box Box 19)
    - Thomas Wentworth Higginson, 1911 (Box Box 20)
    - Brookes More: Galley Proofs of The Beggar's Vision, 1919 & 1921 (Box Box 20)
    - Brookes More's translation of Metamorphoses by Publius Ovidius Naso ( Ovid): Galley Proof, 1922 (Box Box 20)
    - National Poetry Week, 1921 (Box Box 20)
    - Order of Bookfellows, 1921-1927 (Box Box 20)
    - Peabody Master Printers, 1929-1936, n.d. (Box Box 20)
    - Poetry Journal & Poetry Review, 1912-1917, 1930 & n.d. (Box Box 20)
    - Poetry Society of America, 1910-1939, n.d. (Box Box 20)
    - Publishers, 1903-1938; 2 folders (Box Box 20)
    - Clinton Scollard: Lyrics From A Library (unbound pages), ca. 1913-ca. 1917 (Box Box 20)
    - Small, Maynard & Company, 1905-1925 (Box Box 20)
    - Who's Who In America, 1905, 1929, 1933-1939 (Box Box 20)
    - Alabama, Arkansas, 1925-1935 (Box Box 21)
    - California, 1918-1932 (Box Box 21)
    - Colorado, Florida, Georgia, Idaho, 1916, 1925-1933 (Box Box 21)
    - Illinois, Iowa, New Hampshire, Kansas, 1905, 1912-1932 (Box Box 21)
    - Louisiana, Maine, Maryland, 1894, 1913-1937 (Box Box 21)
    - Michigan, Minnesota, Mississippi, Missouri, 1913-1948 (Box Box 21)
    - Montana, Nebraska, New Mexico, North Dakota, 1923-1933 (Box Box 21)
    - Ohio, 1916-1932 (Box Box 21)
    - Oklahoma, Oregon, 1924-1937 (Box Box 21)
    - Pennsylvania, 1909-1935 (Box Box 22)
    - South Carolina, South Dakota, 1923-1935 (Box Box 22)
    - Tennessee, Texas, Utah, 1913-1934 (Box Box 22)
    - Washington, Wisconsin, Wyoming, 1918-1933 (Box Box 22)
- SERIES V: MISCELLANEOUS
  - Astrological Readings for William Stanley Braithwaite, 1904, n.d. (Box Box 22)
  - Delta Phi Delta membership certificate of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1937 (Box Box 22)
  - Financial and Legal Papers, 1903-1936 (Box Box 22)
  - His Idol's Eye and other short stories --page proofs, 1922 Nov 1 (Box Box 22)
  - Lecture Series and Poetry Course Announcements, 1915-1916, 1930-1935 (Box Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1899-1938, n.d. (Box Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, 1923-1929, n.d.; 3 folders (Box Box 23)
    [Including proof of
    The Veiled Door
    by Caroline Giltinan(folder 1) and a typescript of "Since Cezanne" by Clive Bell]
  - Miscellaneous Poetry, 1924-1930 (Box Box 23)
  - Newspaper Clippings re William Stanley Braithwaite, 1908-1934 & 1962, n.d. (Box Box 23)
  - Photographs and Prints, 1913-1914, n.d. (Box Box 23)
  - Poems from birthday book honoring William Stanley Braithwaite, 1958 (Box Box 23)
  - Poet Laureate's Ode, "England, Stand Firm", 1916 (Box Box 23)
  - Poets and Poetry: Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1912, 1927-1935, n.d. (Box Box 23)
  - Poet's Biographical Sketches, 1926 (Box Box 23)
  - William Thackeray& William Dean Howells, n.d. (Box Box 23)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Broadside, Brimmer Books, re The Funny House by Louis Hubert Guyol, 1923 (Box Oversize)
  - Poster, re the 11th annual issue of Braithwaite's Anthology of Magazine Verse, 1923 (Box Oversize)
  - Broadside, Hampton Spirit Special ( Hampton Institute) re upcoming sports events, 1934 Nov 8 (Box Oversize)
  - Photograph of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1959 (Box Oversize)